Finding Aid for the Alice Greenfield McGrath Papers LSC.1490
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 2. Personal papers., 1943-2006
  - 2.3 Miscellaneous., 1958-2006
    - Alice McGrath's Wedding Vows., 1977 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Alice McGrath's personal biographies., 2004 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      Materials gathered for Stanford University's Chicano/Latino theme dorm, Casa Zapata for their annual Zoot Suit Week on February 22, 2004.
    - Alice McGrath's personal notes, telephone numbers, names., ca. 1970-2006 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Grove Press book publisher letters and exhibit photos., 1959 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Personal legal documents, including CA I.D. cards., 1958 October 7-2003 April 5 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - List of items to be gifted to UCLA Special Collections for the Alice McGrath Collection., 2009 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- 3. Photographs., 1941-2009
  Photographs in this series predominantly picture family and friends as well as portraits of Alice McGrath.
  - Family photographs., 1947 October-2007 January (Box 8, Folder 23)
    Mainly of Daniel Schechter.
  - Family photographs., bulk February 2008 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Mainly of Alice McGrath, Daniel Schechter (McGrath's son), and Laura D'Auri (McGrath's daughter).
  - Portraits of Alice McGrath., ca. 1938-2002 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Also includes a digital contact sheet with approximate ages of Alice in various photographs.
  - Various family photographs., 1941 March-2005 December (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Includes photographs of Alice McGrath and her children, Thomas McGrath and other family.
  - Photographs of Alice McGrath and friends., 1942-2009 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Alice McGrath and family., 1950s (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Includes photographs of Alice McGrath, Thomas McGrath, Laura D'Auri, and Daniel Schechter.
  - Alice McGrath and family., 1839-1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Includes photographs of Alice McGrath, her two sisters and her parents.
  - Photographs of friends., ca. 1940s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Includes photographs of Cisco Houston, McGrath's sister Claire, Hasker Wexler, Luisa Moreno, Carlos Bulosan, Ben Maddow, and others unidentified.
  - Soviet Union (Russia) photographs., 1978 February (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Oversize -- portraits of Alice McGrath., ca. 1979 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- 4. Publications and lectures., 1944-1993
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  Consists of articles and books that were given to Alice McGrath. Many of the items have an inscription or signature addressed to McGrath by the author.
  - Various articles with inscriptions or signatures., 1964 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Includes "Selecting a School Counselor" by Laurence Peter, "A Mathematician's Faith" by Dirk Struik, and "It's Your Money" by C. Northcote Parkinson.
  - The Contemporary Man, drawings by Chris Jenkyns with Words by Alice McGrath, unpublished., 1965 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Notes from Underground II with an inscription to Bruce and Alice., 1966 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Fuck You: a magazine of the arts 7, no. 5 (Sept 1964). (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Maddow, Ben.The Savage Eye: A Film on Hogarth in Los Angeles [transcript]., 1952 January 2 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Maddow, Ben.The Savage Eye: A Film on Hogarth in Los Angeles [onion skin draft]., ca. 1952 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Grove Press letters and sales reports., ca. 1960 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - The Essentials in a Struggle- A chapter from W.E.B. DuBois The Suppression of the African Slave Trade to the United States of America 1638-1870., undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    photocopy
  - The Literary Worker's Polonius from A Literary Chronicle by Wilson, Edmund., undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    photocopy from 1935 work.
  - Balter, Michael. Peace, Love, and Fort Ord. Buzz (August 1993): 68-71. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Varat, Harvey.Self-Renewal and the Police Establishment [manuscript]., 1972 May 18 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Hyman,Irwin. Corporal Punishment in the Schools: Americas Officially Sanctioned Brand of Child Abuse. [copy]., 1977 April 18 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Phillips, Ralph S.Dissipative Operators and Hyperbolic Systems of Partial Differential Equations [reprint]. Transactions of the American Mathematical Society 90, no.2 (February 1959): 193-254., 1959 February (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Inscription to Alice McGrath by author.
  - Ming, Kwa Tak.The Fundamental operations in Bead Arithmetic: How to Use the Chinese Abacus. Service Supply Company: San Francisco., undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Grove Press photographs of Alice McGrath and sales displays., ca. 1960 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - The Alpine Weekly Newsletter [photocopy]., 1944 March 30 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Pinter, Harold.Moonlight. Boston: Faber and Faber., 1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Inscription to Alice McGrath from the author.
  - North Dakota Quarterly 50, no. 4 (Fall)., 1982 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Issue includes articles by Thomas McGrath: "Statement to the House Committee on Un-American Activities," "Crazy Horse Manifesto," "McGrath on McGrath," and "The Frontiers of Language." Issue also includes an article by Alice McGrath, "Longshot O'Leary Says It's Your Duty to Be Full of Fury."
  - McGrath, Thomas.Longshot O'Leary's Garland of Practical Poesie. New York: International Publishers., 1949 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Turkel, Studs.Coming of Age: The Story of Our Century by Those Who've Lived It. New York: The New Press, 1995. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Hardback cover with dust jacket. Inscribed to McGrath from Terkel.
  - Recordings of Alice McGrath and Luis Valdez., circa 2001-2009 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Includes 3 DVDs and a letter addressed to Laura D'Auri from Frank Sotomayor. Letter describes the recording on each of the three discs. Recordings include an interview of McGrath by Frank Sotomayor, McGrath lecturing on the Sleepy Lagoon case, a question and answer session with McGrath, and an interview of Luis Valdez about the Zoot Suit play and McGrath. The recordings appear to be transfers from VHS tapes, and the sound and image quality is often poor.
    - Alice McGrath interviewd by Frank Sotomayor at her home in Ventura, undated; yrlsc_1490_010_018_002; Sotomayor, Frank; 1 Video Recordings (1 DVD; 0:31:22) (Box 10, Case 2)
      CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
      Scope and Contents
      Content note: Accompanying letter gives explanation of video content.
    - Alice McGrath lecture and Q and A at UC Santa Cruz, undated; yrlsc_1490_010_018_003; 1 Video Recordings (1 DVD; 01:47:17) (Box 10, Case 3)
    - Luis Valdez on Zoot Suit and Alice, undated; yrlsc_1490_010_018_004; 1 Video Recordings (1 DVD; 1:13:50) (Box 10, Case 4)
  - Alice McGrath interviewed by Luis Valdez at the El Teatro Campesino, 2007-2010. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Includes DVD of interview and a discussion between Alice McGrath and Alika Spencer, the woman who plays McGrath's character in the Zoot Suit play. DVD is in plastic jewel case with a facsimile of a letter Valdez sent to McGrath in 1978. Folder also includes letter from Valdez to Laura D'Auri in 2010 and photograph of Luis, Alice, and others, circa 2007.
    - Alice McGrath interviewed by Luis Valdez at the El Teatro Campesino, 2007-2010; yrlsc_1490_011_001_001; 1 Video Recordings (1 DVD; 0:38:45) (Box 11, Case 1)
      Content note: DVD is in plastic jewel case with a facsimile of a letter Valdez sent to McGrath in 1978.
- 5. China trip., 1979
  Consists of ephemera, travel diary, and photographs of her trip to China.
  - Photograph., 1979 June (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Taken in conjunction with Alice McGrath's English lecture on "Zoot Suit."
  - Alice McGrath's China trip diary., 1979 May 21 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - A Tourist Guide to Chungking and map., 1979 May (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Alice McGrath and others in China., 1979 May (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Postcards, Stamps, and Letters during Alice McGrath's China trip., 1979 May (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Information about China., 1979 May 3 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - McGrath's notebooks containing notes on China Trip., 1979 May-June (Box 11, Folder 8)
- 6. Solidarity work in Nicaragua., 1979-2003
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the file level. All requests to access processed audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  This series relates to McGrath's work in support of the Sandinista National Liberation Front (FLSN) and McGrath's humanitarian tours of the country. Consists of correspondence, ephemera, and photos.
  - Nicaraguan Delegation lists., 1986 June (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Includes letter and programs of events.
  - Center for Training in Computer Science and Systems (CAIS) -- microcomputer training project., 1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Also includes letters to McGrath about her donations.
  - Correspondence and photographs., ca. 1987-1998 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Sandinista Constitution., 1987 January 9 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Copy of constitutional reform provided by the Nicaraguan Embassy.
  - La Seaman Comical Newspaper and other newspaper clippings., 1984 March 18- 1992 May 26 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Memoria Ejercito de Nicaragua 1995-1997. Managua: Direccion de Relaciones Publicas y Exteriores., 1998 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Instituto Nicaraguense de Seguridad Social y Bienestar. Martirio De Los Niños De Nicaragua Bajo La Agresion De La Administracion Regan. Managua: Instituto Nicaraguense de Seguridad Social y Bienestar., 1985 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Also includes The Subversive Agent (For A Poetry of Revolutionary Activism).
  - Torres, Sylvia. Una 'chela' con algo extra. Barrada supplement, Managua., 1994 September (Box 11, Folder 16)
    Note written by Alice McGrath and stuck to article indicates the article is "loaded with inaccuracies."
  - Photographs., 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Photographs picture Alice McGrath delivering supplies to a Nicaraguan children's hospital, Sergio Ramirez (Vice President from 1984-1990), Mary Addes, Xabier Gorostiaga and LASA.
  - Photographs -- Alice McGrath with campesinos and companeros., 1987-1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Many of the photographs included are laminated.
  - Photographs -- tours., ca. 1980 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Photographs -- American farmers with Alice McGrath (in Nicaragua)., 1990 February (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Photographs -- murals in Managua Church that was to be painted over., ca. 1980s (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Photographs -- Alice McGrath in children's hospitals and schools., 1989 June (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Photographs -- people voting and FSLN supporters., 1990 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Photographs -- Alice McGrath on her 25th trip to Nicaragua., 1989 June (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Photographs -- Cuban veterinarians and doctors delegation., ca. 1980s (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Photographs -- American Citizens demonstrating., 1984-1986 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Photograph -- McGrath with Daniel Nunez., ca. 1980 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Nuñez was president of UNAG (National Farmer's and Cattleman's Association of Nicaragua).
  - Photograph -- clergy delegation and Soviet Circus., ca.1986-1988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Photograph -- Dr. Fernando Silva and army base., 1984-1990 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Photograph -- La Orden Decimo Aniversario for solidarity work., 1990 February 23 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    Includes clippings and the medal McGrath received.
  - Certificate from Frente Sandinista de la Liberacion Nacional to Alice McGrath., 1979 Jul 19 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    Awarded to recognize McGrath's support of the Sandinistas.
  - Photograph -- Alice McGrath with Daniel Ortega., ca. 1980s (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Cards and Postcards from Nicaragua., ca. 1988 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Nicaraguan currency and stamp., ca. 1980 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Commemorative day planner., 1989 July 19-1990 December 31 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    10th Anniversary Celebration Calendar (planner) of the triumph of the Nicaraguan Revolution from July 19, 1989 to December 30, 1990
  - Election ephemera., ca. 1984 November 4 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    The Electoral Process in Nicaragua: Domestic and International Influences, Electoral Law pamphlet, sample ballot.
  - Photographs and slides., ca. 2001-2003 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    Includes slides taken in Nicaragua, photos of AM with Lewites, Herty (Mayor of Managua) and other companeros, inscription from author Gioconda Bellis.
  - Alice G. McGrath at Cal State University Channel Islands, 2003 March 6 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Alice G. McGrath at Cal State University Channel Islands, 2003 March 6; yrlsc_1490_012_023a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; 0:31:11) (Box 12, Case 23)
      Content note: Alice interveiwed by CSU professor, Frank Barajas
    - Alice G. McGrath at Cal State University Channel Islands, 2003 March 6; yrlsc_1490_012_023b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; 0:06:40) (Box 12, Case 23)
  - Photograph -- Sandino., ca. 1980 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - ¡Nicaragua mi muchachita! Commemorative posters of the Frente Sandinista de la Liberacion Nacional., 1986 November 8 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Patria Libre Newspaper, Triunfo Sandinista Pueblo Nicaraguense llega al poder (Sandinista Triumph)., 1979 July 19 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - En Confianza Alicia en el pais de los desastres. Supplement to Nosotras de La Prensa., 2002 April 23 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Nicaraguan election ephemera., ca. 1990 March (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Oversize -- clippings and ephemera., 1982 August 12-1990 May 13 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Frente Sandinista de la Liberacion Nacional scarf., ca. 1980s (Box 15, Folder 1)
    This is the same scarf Alice McGrath is wearing in the photograph with Daniel Ortega
- 7. Awards and recognitions., 1981-2008
  Consists of general recognitions, awards, and thank you notes. The awards and letters predominantly relate to McGrath's political activism.
  - Thank you letters -- lectures and appearances., 1981 March 23-2007 June (Box 12, Folder 21)
    This folder contains various letters from institutions where Alice McGrath served on a panel or gave a lecture. Many of these lectures were on the topic of the Sleep Lagoon trial.
  - Sheldon, Glenn. Interview with Alice McGrath.Pittsburgh Quarterly (Winter 1991/92). (Box 12, Folder 22)
    Includes print out of article and letter to Alice McGrath from the author.
  - Letter from Los Angeles Mayor Tom Bradley congratulating McGrath on her 70th Birthday, newspaper clippings about her birthday celebration., 1987 April 5 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - McGrath's 75th birthday celebration -- clippings., 1992 April 5 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - McGrath's 90th birthday celebration -- clippings., 2007 April 22 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Ventura County Board of Supervisors recognition of McGrath's 80th birthday., 1997 April 5 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Coming of Age: The Story of Our Century by those Who've Lived it by Studs Terkel -- clippings., 1992 April 6-1995 November 7 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper articles and clippings discussing McGrath's fight for social justice, involvement with Sleepy Lagoon Trial., 1995 September 17-2002 March 4 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Alice McGrath lecture advertisements., 1996 October 16 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Sotomayor, Frank. "Patron Saint of Lost Causes."Los Angeles Times Magazine, February 3, 2002. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Davis, Kelly. "Go Ask Alice." Ventura County Reporter, November 1, 2001. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - El Concilio del Condado de Ventura Tenth Annual Latino Leadership Awards., 1999 January 3 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - County of Ventura Leadership Award., 1999 January 3 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Cruz Reynoso Award., 1998 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    This folder contains the program for the 38th annual banquet of the Mexican American Bar Association.
  - The Rotary Foundation of Rotary International., 2001 May (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Certificate recognizes Alice McGrath as a benefactor of the Rotary Foundation.
  - Various Certificates of Recognition., 1996-1998 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Clippings -- Alice McGrath's awards and recognitions., 1998 October 29-2008 September 25 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - University of California, Santa Cruz commencement program., 1997 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Alice McGrath gave the keynote speech at the commencement.
  - Invitations., ca. 1996 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Invitations are to a testimonial dinner honoring several attorneys, as well as to meet with Wallace, Henry
  - Progressive LA Conference ephemera., 1998 Oct 3 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    This folder includes clippings, a letter, and programming information for the conference.
  - Ventura County Bar Association., 1996 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    McGrath served as the association's Pro Bono Program manager.
  - Black Journalists Association of Southern Californian newsletter., 1982 July (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Newsletter mentions McGrath's appearance at the July meeting of the association.
  - University of Washington's Labor Studies Department -- appreciation for Alice McGrath's donations., 2002 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Center for Constitutional Rights newsletter., 2008 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Materials in this folder relate to McGrath's donations and fundraising efforts. Also includes photographs of Alice McGrath with various members of the center.
  - McGrath's 70th birthday celebration invitation., 1987 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Includes photographs with Sleepy Lagoon trial defendants.
  - McGrath's 85th birthday celebration -- programs., 2002 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - McGrath's 85th birthday celebration -- clippings., 2002 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - McGrath's 85th birthday celebration -- photographs., 2002 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - McGrath's 90th birthday celebration -- ephemera., 2007 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Oversized awards, certificates, and posters given to McGrath., 1992-2002 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - National Women's Political Caucus of Ventura County 2003 Women's History Calendar. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Ventura College Associate in Arts Diploma and Ventura College commencement program., 10 June 1983 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Alice McGrath served as student speaker.
  - La Raza Faculty Association plaque, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 8. Government investigation files., 1943-1980
  Both Alice McGrath and her son, Daniel Schechter, were investigated by the Federal Bureau of Investigation at different times in history. This series consists of documentation of the investigations by the F.B.I. and the Immigration and Naturalization Services.
  - Freedom of Information Act releases -- Alice McGrath., 1952 November 11-1968 November 1 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Official release interleaved with McGrath's personal notes.
  - Freedom of Information Act releases -- Joseph B. Goldberg., 1980 April 28-November 2 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence between Joseph B. Goldberg, FBI Freedom of Information Branch, and Army Intelligence., 1979 November 17- 1980 February 2 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Freedom of Information Act releases -- Thomas McGrath., 1943 May 21-1957 January 2 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Max Schechter single sheet report about his business., 1963 May 3 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- 9. Self-defense., 1961-1980
  Consists of the documentation of McGrath's career in teaching, writing about, and demonstrating self-defense techniques. Series includes photographs, correspondence, and articles.
  - Photographs where McGrath is practicing and demonstrating self-defense tactics, newspaper articles about McGrath's self-defense course., ca. 1974 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Clippings about Alice McGrath's writings and courses on self-defense., 1962 April- 1980 August 19 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Newspaper articles and clippings (from the LA Times and Chicago Tribune) about McGrath's self-defense courses, "How to Become a Martial Arts Book Expert Without Hitting Anybody" by McGrath, "Self-Defense for Cowards" by Alice McGrath, letters about course
  - California Community College's certificate of special limited services credential., 1972 September 18 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Descriptions and brochures for defense classes., 1973-1975 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and descriptions for defense classes (folder 1 of 2)., 1967 August 30-1980 March 15 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    Letters to McGrath about her self-defense course from schools, Journal of physical education and recreation, California Physical Ed. Workshop booklet, Self Defense & Assault Prevention for Girls and Women seminar conducted by McGrath.
  - Correspondence and descriptions for defense classes (folder 2 of 2)., 1967 August 30-1980 March 15 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - McGrath, Alice and Chris Jenkyns. Better Part of Valor. The Sunday Telegraph, page 5., 1962 June 24 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - McGrath, Alice. How to Become a Martial Arts Book Expert without Hitting Anybody. Top of the News 34, no. 4 (Summer 1978):331-338. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Tegner, Bruce and Alice McGrath.The Survival Book. New York: Bantam Books, 1983. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Photographs -- examples of self-defense techniques., ca. 1960 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - McGrath, Alice.Self-Defense for Cowards. Hollywood, CA: Thor Publications Co., 1961. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Drawings by Chris Jenkyns. One copy has an inscription by Stan Freberg and Chris Jenkyns.
  - Tegner, Bruce and Alice McGrath.Self-Defense and Assault Prevention for Girls and Women. Hollywood, CA: Thor Publications Co., 1986. (Box 17, Folder 7)
- 10. Memorial ephemera., 2009
  Consists of letters, cards, sound and video recordings, and other materials received by Laura D'Auri or created for McGrath's memorial ceremony.
  CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Digital and audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
  - Obituaries., 2009 November (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Includes copies of the obituaries run in the Los Angeles Times, the Ventura Star, and the Los Angeles Daily Journal.
  - List of invitees to McGrath's memorial ceremony., 2009 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Memorial announcements., 2009 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Funeral guest book., 2009 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Condolence correspondence., 2009-2010 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Included in this folder are letters of condolence written to Laura D'Auri, McGrath's daughter. Letters included from Lee Ann Meyer, John F. Terzano (The Justice Project), James Gregory (Harry Bridges Center for Labor Studies), Fernando Gamboa, Gus and Lamont Yeakey and others.
  - Slide show shown at memorial., 2009 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Consists of 1 DVD and 2 CDs, all of which have some variation of a slide show featuring pictures of Alice McGrath at various points in her life. The slide shows consist of 34 images, captions and music.
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
  - DVD recorded at memorial., 2009 December (Box 17, Folder 13)
    Folder includes 2 DVDs: a regular version and an HD version. Speakers include: Steve Stone, Arthur Gilbert, Steve Perrin, Greg Totten, Kevi Brannelly, Tom Crossure, Holly Olsen (McGrath's niece), Josie Saldano, and others.
  - University of California at Los Angeles - digital images for memorial., 2009 (Box 17, Folder 14)